Contact

A405, AS-AK, Al Ghubaiba, Dubai, UAE +971-588600185 (Mobile) udayom@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/udayom (LinkedIn) udayom.blogspot.com (Blog) github.com/udayom (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Threat & Vulnerability Management Cyber Operations Vulnerability Assessment

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Marathi (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Cloud Computing

Agile Project Management And Agile Delivery (Crash Course)

Symantec Endpoint Protection -SEP, ATP, WSS, Email Security Linux Lab

ISO/IEC 27001 LA

Publications

Interference Analysis of IEEE 802.11n

Optimum Utilization of Private cloud with predefined Reservation Policy

UDAY KUMAR LOKHANDE

Cyber Security Researcher | GRC | ISO 27001 LA | PCI DSS Implementation | CEHv10 | DevSecOps | Agile | Life-Time Learner

Summary

With 6+ Years of Total Experience, Uday has been successful in implementing Policy and Procedures as per ISO 27001 standards in various projects, he has also implemented procedures based on PCI DSS and PA DSS standard and Handled Internal Auditing of same.

He has expertly performed Vulnerability Analysis and Penetration Testings (Web Application, Server, Mobile, all platforms) and he is good in defending the Infrastructure from External Cyber Attacks (Blue Team Lead). He can forensically analyze the origin of Cyber attack & trace the behavior/malware/unintentional/hacking activity.

Uday has also evaluated risk assessment for business as part of compliance due diligence. He holds DevOps / DevSecOps & Agile Methodology experience as well, always looking for the scope of Automation in Infrastructure/process/IT and he loves open source tools used for Cyber Forensics, Ethical Hacking, VAPT activities. Having teaching background Uday can teach, explain concepts very well to Juniors as well as senior Management with ease.

Top Highlights: (Client Facing)
Presenting
Demonstrating
Delivering
Investigating (RCA)

Certificates:

ISO 27001 Lead Auditor (TuV SuD)
PCI DSS Implementation (Qrc)
Certified Ethical Hacking CEH v10 (EC-Council)
Agile Project Management (Udemy)
Diploma in Cyber Law (Asian School of Cyber Law)

Trainings Attended:

Cyber Forensic & Crime Investigation (University Certification)

Page 1 of 7

ITIL Foundation (L & D)
AWS DevOps (Seminar)
DevSecOps (L & D)
Cloud Computing (University Certification)
Linux Lab (University Certification)

Experience

Khidmaty Government Services Cyber Security Consultant April 2018 - Present

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Operational and Governance related tasks that relates to Security for Client ASGC, Dubai. Major task includes the Defining and Implementation of Information Security Policies and Procedures as per ISO27001 Standards.

The Automation of Management Reports, Analyze the vulnerabilities found in infrastructure by Vulnerability Analysis and Penetration Testing (Manual +Automated), Threat Remediation, highlight risk to management, risk assessment, vendor management, security checks for vendor, hardening checks on the Oracle Linux operating system, schedule Antivirus scans and highlight the Major vulnerability to IT Infra team, schedule patch management, Ensure compliance of the policies on the servers, Manage and Administer IT security and Forensic tools such as LanSweeper, QualysGuard, Symantec Endpoint protection, ATP, ETP, EDR, MS Office 365 Admin, Azure Portal Admin, Cloud Server Management Activities like New Provisioning server, Migrate, Destroy server etc.

Perform VAPT on in-house Applications using OpenVAS. SIEM configuration (AlienVault), Cyber Operations, Reporting, Demonstration. Investigation of the attacks, Fortinet Firewall Rules review (nipper), log and memory based analysis, Forensic evidence finding (SIEM Log and Dump based)

Technical Policy defining and Implementation in Symantec Endpoint Protection, Data Leakage Protection (DLP), Email+Cloud Security, Email Threat Protection (FireEye, Microsoft, Mimecast), Web Isolation modules

Finacus Solutions
IT Security Manager
June 2017 - April 2018 (11 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Automation with Security Compliance checks, Policy procedures defining, ISO/IEC 27001, PCI-DSS implementation, Process Management, Incident Management, Change management, Automation of operational tasks, Internal Security Auditing, VAPT, Continuous Development and Automation with open-source tools (DevOps), Complete Financial Domain, Payment gateway interface Audit as per PCI DSS Compliance, Process Auditing. Reporting ROC (Report on Compliance), ROV (Report on Validation), Performing ASV Scans as part of PCI DSS Implementation.

Major Responsibility included all the Operational and Governance related tasks that relates to Security for Finacus Solutions Pvt. Ltd. which deals with its various clients (100+) as Reputed Banks spread across India.

Major task included the Defining and Implementation of Information Security Policies and Procedures. The Automation of business requirements and management, so far covered Change management, Incident Management, Asset Inventory, Helpdesk, Ticketing, Effort Tracking and Documentation storage Automation. Administering Azure account for system integration of ticketing system

From DevSecOps section, have covered configuration, implementation and Maintenance of various monitoring tool such as Nagios, Baretail, OpenNMS, Graylog, RanCID. Automated Email/SMS Triggering from monitoring tool if critical alert arrives as per business requirement. Configuring and Administration of Manage Engine PIM Tool Password Manager Pro, WatchGuard Firewall Rules, Implementing Trend Micro Anti-Virus, Involvement of banking domain requires more emphasize on PCI-DSS compliance which talks about internal and external Auditing reports. Jenkins Automation for day to day jobs as well as code deployment on Linux servers via Shell Scripts developed and implemented.

Following Agile Way of Methodology with Sprint Framework and DevSecOps Practice to achieve Automation with End to End Project workflow Integration including Automated Security Check Components!

Capgemini
Cyber Security Analyst
November 2014 - June 2017 (2 years 8 months)
Mumbai Area. India

>>> Governance Security:

Manage Audits, Compliance check along with certifications for various standards such as ISO 27001:2013 and PCI DSS. Multi-operational experience in Networking Operations, Systems Administration, Security and Audit & Support of Heterogeneous IT Infrastructure and BCP/DR. Handling Incident Management.

Formulating, Reviewing, Upgrading, Developing Policy, Procedures and Guidelines for elements governing/connected to ISO Standards, Analyze SIEM tools, IDS and auctioning on alerts.

>>> Operational Security:

Involved in Vulnerability Analysis and Penetration Testing, worked on tools like burpsuite, IBM Appscanner, OWASP top 10, wapiti, Paros proxy, Nikto, Nessus, metasploite etc.

IPS and DDOS mitigation device reports analysis firewall rule dump and analysis, proxy logs, user administration, OSSEC, SIEM tool monitoring and configuration, ITIL Tool - Service now.

Cyber Forensics and Analysis using tools like The Sleuth Kit, Autopsy, Rekall, DumpIT, Volatility, log2timeline and most of the tools from Kali Linux OS. Handled SOC activities in which Analysis of complete trail of activities of user based on the logs and extracting footprints for legal purpose to be dealt with Cyber Law team.

>>> DevOps:

Digital Transformation of Project: Worked on Multiple open source tools like Nagios, Munin, graphite, Jenkins, Apache, Idap, mongodb, maven, Exim, ELK stack, graylog, graphite, redis-cache, memcache, exim, Linux shell scripting, Automation with Jenkins, Ansible, Puppet

To design business rule-based dashboards in AppDynamic. To make dashboards and alerts in AppDynamics based on Business requirement. AppDynamics deployment and complete setup

>>> Project Management:

Experience on Atlassian tools like JIRA, Confluence, stash, bitbucket. Studied ITIL Fv4 & worked on Kanban boards for project progress tracking. Project management experience for deployment, schedule.

Good at Incident, Change management, onshore & offshore interaction & Documentation

Asian Associates
Engineer Internship
December 2013 - November 2014 (1 year)
Mumbai Area, India

Performed Vulnerability Analysis and Penetration Testing, worked on Linux based open source tools like burpsuite, OWASP, Nikto, wapiti, Paros proxy, Nessus, metasploite etc.

Implemented and Administered IPS and Performed DDOS mitigation device reports analysis, Forensic Analysis on attack trace, proxy logs, user administration.

Complete SOC level Monitoring setup including Nagios, OSSEC, SIEM tool monitoring and configuration.

Tweaking in existing scripts/IT Tools for performance boosting and Automating of the tasks performed.

*This is While in Full Time Master Degree Program (Project research and Engineer Internship overlaps)

Terna Engineering College
Teaching Associate & Practical Lab Assistant
December 2012 - December 2013 (1 year 1 month)
Mumbai Area, India

Worked as Teaching Associate @ Terna Engineering College, Nerul, Navi Mumbai.

Subjects taught to Engineering Students : Linux, Cloud Computing, Network Security, Practicals.

Worked as Practical Lab Assistant where major responsibility emphasis on Security Measures while developing the application in cloud and on-premise infrastructure. (as a part of Masters' first year). Worked on Wireshark, tcpdump tools uesd to monitor the run-time user traffic for security measures.

Worked on Linux (4 years) tools like telnet, ssh basic concepts that were required for project work to take ahead.

Worked on the multiple VAPT (Vulnerability Analysis and Penetration Testing) tools such as acutinex, nikto, wapiti, metasploit, nessus etc to find out vulnerability in website CVE/CWE references and possible solution to fix them.

Got appreciation from Principal regarding good with documentation and presentations.

Got Bounty from principal for finding miss-configuration in cyberoam device in college Infrastructure.

Work from Cyber Security Forensic Analysis field, IPS device, UTM hardware devices (Cyberoam), firewalls, Implemented ISMS policy in theory, IP-tracing, reputation, spam detection, vulnerability testing, penetration testing, CVE findings. (White Hat Hacking)

Cloud based Instance customization: To make instance more efficient. (IAAS)

Proof reading logs: Log file analysis

VMWare and virtualization technologies.

Router configuration: Implementing / routing paths for efficient routing, making subnets.

Representing graphs in sophisticated graphical format using open source tools/

Interaction + Presentation for clients / Representatives. Vendor finalization for Security stack assets.

*This is While in Full Time Master Degree Program (Project research and Teaching together overlaps)

Education

Terna Engineering College, Mumbai University

Master of Engineering - MEng, Information Technology · (2012 - 2014)

Welingkar Institute of Management

Master of Business Administration - MBA, HPGD - eBusiness · (2015 - 2017)

Asian School of Cyber Laws
Diploma in Cyber Laws, Cyber/Computer Forensics and
Counterterrorism · (2017 - 2018)

Sardar Patel Institute of Technology, Mumbai University
Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics & Telecommunication · (2008 - 2012)

Parle Tilak Vidyalaya Associations Sathaye College Dixit Road Vile Parle East Mumbai 400 057
Higher Secondary School, Electrical, Electronics and Communications

Engineering · (2006 - 2008)